ana estrada

software developer www.anaestrada.es

behance.net/aemartos github.com/aemartos linkedin.com/in/aemartos

about

Software developer, graphic and web designer specialized in UI-UX, photographer, amateur typographer, deeply creative, small-time cinephile, shower singer, hardened reader, geocacher, incessant traveller, chameleon and autodidact by nature, oversociable and tireless fighter.

skills

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, ES6, TypeScript, jQuery, React, Redux, AJAX, Apollo GraphQL, Next.js, Nest.js, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL & Express.

Software: Adobe CC (Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects, Illustrator, InDesign, XD, Audition...), Sketch, Principle, Glyphs, iWork.

Languages: Spanish (native) and English (high level).
Cambridge English: FCE.

awards

IronHack Hackshow 2019: Best Web Development project.

TadHack 2018: <u>Drugon</u>
1st local award by UPM.
2nd award by Kairos.

Gold Laus 2018: Dana Font

CLAP to the best experimental typography 2018: <u>Dana Font</u>

Award to Educational Innovation Group 2017: GIE Cyberaula

HackForGood 2016: Aprendis

1st award local by Telefónica. 1st award by U.Comillas. 3th award by Telefónica - UPM.

work experience

Capchase

Madrid, Spain. Dec 2020 - present.

Software developer

Involvement in different projects from frontend to backend developments. REST API, functionality design, UX implementation on the client platform and backoffice.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JS, ES6, React, Vue, TypeScript, Jest, Postman, MongoDB, SQL, Node.js & Express.

Bnext

Madrid, Spain. Sept 2019 - Dec 2020.

Backend developer

At Core Banking System Team. Design, develop, maintain and upgrade the integration of Bnext 2.0. (Card life cycle, customer onboarding and registration, KYC, AML, third party gateways, REST API, microservices...)

Technologies: JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, Jest, Postman, MongoDB, SQL, Nest.js, Node.js & Express.

BinPar Digital Ignition

Las Rozas, Madrid, Spain. March 2019 - Sept 2019.

Fullstack developer

Design, management and development of solutions for innovative projects. SEO optimization Improved e-commerce development with GA.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, SASS, JS, ES6, React, Apollo GraphQL, Next.js, MongoDB, Node.js, Express, Git & GitFlow.

GING UPM

Polytechnic University. Madrid, Spain. Sept 2017 - March 2019.

Frontend developer and UX-UI designer

UX-UI design, interface and product design responsible. Front-End development to interactive responsive solutions. Researcher in group projects in fields related to ITC development and use.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JS, React, WP, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Node.js, Express. AdobeCC & iWork.

Barfutura

Madrid, Spain. Feb - July 2017.

Graphic designer

Branding and corporate identity. Photography, digital retouching and poster design. Layout, design and web development.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Wordpress, AdobeCC & iWork.

Derepente Madrid

Madrid, Spain. June - Nov 2016.

Graphic and web designer

Branding, corporate identity and advertising. Layout, design and web development, WordPress.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Wordpress, AdobeCC & iWork.

education

Ironhack - Web Development: Part-Time program.

SEPT18 - MAR19

Escuela Superior de Diseño de Madrid (ESD)

Master of Interactive Design. (UX - UI & web development). Bachelor degree of Graphic Design.

SEPT17 - JUN18 SEPT13 - JUN17

Escuela de Arte número diez

Higher Level Training Cycle on Artistic Photography.

SEPT11 - MAR14